<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mathematics on Amin Physics</title>
    <link>https://aminphysicsai.github.io/tags/mathematics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mathematics on Amin Physics</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://aminphysicsai.github.io/tags/mathematics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Mathematical Mystery of Creation</title>
      <link>https://aminphysicsai.github.io/posts/chapter-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminphysicsai.github.io/posts/chapter-two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Mathematical Mystery of Creation: Science, Entropy, and the Question of God&#xA;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Humanity has always searched for its origin. Modern science suggests that our universe began approximately 13.8 billion years ago with the Big Bang. This model explains cosmic expansion, background radiation, and the formation of matter. Yet one profound question remains unanswered:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What existed before the beginning?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Did time itself start at the Big Bang? If so, what does “before” even mean? Science provides models, but not ultimate answers. And it is within this boundary of knowledge that deeper philosophical questions emerge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Physics Becomes a Way of Thinking</title>
      <link>https://aminphysicsai.github.io/posts/chapter-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminphysicsai.github.io/posts/chapter-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter One: When Physics Becomes a Way of Thinking&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Consciousness, Mathematics, Emotion, and the Silent Intelligence of Nature&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article marks the beginning of a chapter-wise series, written not merely to study physics, but to experience it as a philosophy of existence. Here, physics is not reduced to formulas and problem-solving techniques. Instead, it is approached as a deep lens through which reality, consciousness, emotions, and nature reveal their hidden unity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Physics Becomes a Way of Thinking</title>
      <link>https://aminphysicsai.github.io/posts/chapter04/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminphysicsai.github.io/posts/chapter04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Physics Becomes a Way of Thinking&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Physics sirf ek subject nahi hai. Physics ek nazariya hai. Ek tareeqa hai dekhne ka, sochne ka, aur existence ko samajhne ka. Jab physics equations se aage badh kar perception ban jaati hai, tab woh sirf mechanics, thermodynamics ya electromagnetism nahi rehti — woh thinking ka structure ban jaati hai.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sab kuch fields se shuru hota hai. Space khaali nahi hota. Har jagah ek dynamic structure present hota hai — fields. In fields me disturbance hoti hai, aur disturbance vibration ke roop me propagate karti hai. Stable vibration ko hum particle kehte hain. Yani matter ek solid cheez nahi, balki sustained oscillation hai.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From the Origin of Consciousness to the Depth of Physics and Mathematical Intuition</title>
      <link>https://aminphysicsai.github.io/posts/origin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminphysicsai.github.io/posts/origin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Consciousness is perhaps the most intimate mystery we experience and yet the most distant in explanation. We wake, we feel, we think, and we know that we know. This simple fact—awareness of being aware—has puzzled philosophers, scientists, and mystics for centuries. To trace the origin of consciousness is not merely to study the brain, but to journey through physics, mathematics, and the deep structure of reality itself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At its surface, consciousness appears biological. Neurons fire, networks form, and chemical signals flow. But biology alone does not answer &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; these processes give rise to subjective experience. Why should electrical activity produce color, emotion, meaning, or selfhood? This question forces us beyond biology into the foundational laws that govern matter and energy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
