<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Amin Physics</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Amin Physics</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Experience Time</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-emotions-experience-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-emotions-experience-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What Time Is, When Thought Can No Longer Hold It&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Time is the most familiar mystery human beings live inside. Everything happens in time, yet no discipline can fully agree on what time is. Scientists measure it, philosophers question it, psychologists feel it, biologists obey it, and mathematicians describe it—but at the deepest level, time resists containment. It stretches beyond equations, beyond language, beyond certainty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the edge of every discipline, thought reaches a limit—and stops.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Emotions Experience Time</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-emotions-experience-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-emotions-experience-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;reading_time-8-minutes&#34;&gt;title: &amp;ldquo;How Emotions Experience Time&amp;rdquo;&#xA;description: &amp;ldquo;A deep psychological and philosophical exploration of how emotions shape, distort, and recreate time beyond clocks and calendars.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;slug: how-emotions-experience-time&#xA;date: 2026-01-25&#xA;reading_time: &amp;ldquo;~8 minutes&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-emotions-think-about-time&#34;&gt;How Emotions Think About Time&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Time, as measured by clocks, moves with mechanical indifference. Seconds follow seconds with perfect equality. Yet emotional time obeys no such order. It stretches, compresses, loops, freezes, and dissolves—shaped not by physics, but by feeling. Emotions do not experience time as a line; they experience it as a landscape. To understand how emotions “think” about time is to understand how human life actually unfolds from within.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entropy and Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/entropy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/entropy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The room was quiet—almost disciplined. Books were aligned, time was available, effort was possible. Nothing, on the surface, was wrong. Yet his mind felt strangely untethered. An unnamed emptiness lingered, seeping into his thoughts like a slow fog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He wondered how disorder could grow even in stillness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The question did not arise from chaos, but from silence—&#xA;from the unsettling realization that external order does not always guarantee inner coherence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Silent Nature of Decay&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Invisible Structures of Reality</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dark-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dark-energy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Invisible Structures: Dark Matter, Entropy, and the Human Search for Order&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The universe appears luminous and structured on the surface. Stars shine, galaxies rotate gracefully, and physical laws seem orderly and precise. Yet, modern physics reveals a profound truth beneath this apparent clarity: most of what governs the universe is invisible. Dark matter, entropy, and chaotic dynamics quietly shape reality without announcing themselves. In understanding these concepts together, we also uncover something deeply human—our constant struggle to create meaning and order within uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Physics Becomes a Way of Thinking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/chapter-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/chapter-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter One: When Physics Becomes a Way of Thinking&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Consciousness, Mathematics, Emotion, and the Silent Intelligence of Nature&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article marks the beginning of a chapter-wise series, written not merely to study physics, but to experience it as a philosophy of existence. Here, physics is not reduced to formulas and problem-solving techniques. Instead, it is approached as a deep lens through which reality, consciousness, emotions, and nature reveal their hidden unity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From the Origin of Consciousness to the Depth of Physics and Mathematical Intuition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/origin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/origin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Consciousness is perhaps the most intimate mystery we experience and yet the most distant in explanation. We wake, we feel, we think, and we know that we know. This simple fact—awareness of being aware—has puzzled philosophers, scientists, and mystics for centuries. To trace the origin of consciousness is not merely to study the brain, but to journey through physics, mathematics, and the deep structure of reality itself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At its surface, consciousness appears biological. Neurons fire, networks form, and chemical signals flow. But biology alone does not answer &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; these processes give rise to subjective experience. Why should electrical activity produce color, emotion, meaning, or selfhood? This question forces us beyond biology into the foundational laws that govern matter and energy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interconnected Knowledge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/unified-field/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/unified-field/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Invisible Network of Knowledge: How Physics, Mathematics, Biology, Chemistry, Philosophy, and Psychology Form One Living System&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At first glance, human knowledge appears fragmented. Physics studies matter and energy, mathematics deals with abstract patterns, chemistry examines reactions, biology explores life, philosophy questions meaning, and psychology tries to understand the human mind. These disciplines are often taught as separate subjects, divided by textbooks, departments, and terminology. Yet beneath this apparent separation lies a profound truth: all knowledge is deeply interlinked, forming a single, elegant network that explains the complexity of the world and the depth of human experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My New Article</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/new-article-electric-fiels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/new-article-electric-fiels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Insaan apni zindagi me Electric Field ki tarah kaam karta hai&amp;hellip;..&#xA;Electric field wo jagah hoti hai jahan force lagti hai, jahan kuch hona hi hai&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&#xA;Zindagi me ye field hoti hai majboori, bhook, ambition, dar, zimmedari, competition. &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;.&#xA;Insaan in fields ke beech move karta hai, react karta hai, fight karta hai, girta hai, uthta hai.&#xA;Yeh sab present ka pressure hai&amp;hellip;..&#xA;Lekin jo cheez reh jaati hai, wo Potential hoti hai&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;.&#xA;Potential koi force nahi hai  wo memory hai&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;.&#xA;Insaan ne kis jagah kya mehsoos kiya, kya socha, kya sacrifice kiya, kis ko hurt kiya, kis ko heal kiya &amp;hellip;.&#xA;yeh sab space me record ho jaata hai, jaise electric potential space me store hota hai&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;.&#xA;Ap kisi kamre me jaate ho aur bina kisi wajah ke bhari lagta hai&amp;hellip;.&#xA;wo wahi potential hai&amp;hellip; beeti hui emotions ka..&#xA;Insaan mar jaata hai, uska electric field khatam ho jaata hai &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;.&#xA;wo ab kisi ko push nahi karta.&#xA;Lekin uski potential energy &amp;hellip;yade, dard, love, ideas wo reh jaati hain.&#xA;Isliye duniya force se nahi chalti,&#xA;yaadon ke potential se chalti hai&amp;hellip;&#xA;Hamari ek sachchi baat, ek imandaar kaam, ek deep soch&#xA;kisi future ke dil ko bina touch kiye bhi chhoo sakti hai&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&#xA;Jaise charged shell ke andar field zero hota hai&amp;hellip;..&#xA;par potential zinda rehta hai&#xA;waise hi insaan khud chup ho jaata hai,&#xA;par uski kahani space me ghoomti rehti hai.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Love Physics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-i-love-physics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 02:24:49 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-i-love-physics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Physics is not just equations and numbers for me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is the language through which the universe whispers its secrets.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I look at the night sky, I don’t just see stars —&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I see time, gravity, and ancient light traveling across billions of years.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I love physics because it teaches me humility.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No matter how much we know, reality is always deeper.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This website is my journey —&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;to understand nature, thought, and existence through physics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
