<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Foundations on Amin Physics</title>
    <link>https://aminphysicsai.github.io/categories/foundations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Foundations on Amin Physics</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://aminphysicsai.github.io/categories/foundations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Entropy Speaks: The Hidden Architecture of Reality</title>
      <link>https://aminphysicsai.github.io/posts/chapter05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminphysicsai.github.io/posts/chapter05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;entropy-speaks-the-hidden-architecture-of-reality&#34;&gt;Entropy Speaks: The Hidden Architecture of Reality&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://aminphysicsai.github.io/images/entropy-universe.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Entropy Universe&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-if-entropy-had-a-voice&#34;&gt;Introduction: If Entropy Had a Voice&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What if entropy could speak?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not as a textbook definition.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Not as a thermodynamic formula.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But as the silent force shaping time, stars, consciousness, and the destiny of the universe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In statistical mechanics, entropy is defined as:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;S = k ln(Ω)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Where Ω represents the number of microscopic configurations consistent with a macroscopic state.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Entropy is not disorder.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creator, Creation aur Mathematical Universe ka Rahasya</title>
      <link>https://aminphysicsai.github.io/posts/chapter-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminphysicsai.github.io/posts/chapter-three/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Creator, Creation aur Mathematical Mystery of Existence&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kabhi aapne sach me ruk kar socha hai… hum kahan se aaye?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Science kehta hai — Big Bang.&#xA;13.8 billion saal pehle ek extremely dense aur hot state thi. Phir expansion hua. Space bana. Time bana. Matter bana.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lekin sawal wahi reh jata hai —&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Expansion se pehle kya tha?&#xA;Agar time hi Big Bang ke saath start hua, toh “pehle” ka matlab kya hai?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mathematical Mystery of Creation</title>
      <link>https://aminphysicsai.github.io/posts/chapter-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminphysicsai.github.io/posts/chapter-two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Mathematical Mystery of Creation: Science, Entropy, and the Question of God&#xA;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Humanity has always searched for its origin. Modern science suggests that our universe began approximately 13.8 billion years ago with the Big Bang. This model explains cosmic expansion, background radiation, and the formation of matter. Yet one profound question remains unanswered:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What existed before the beginning?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Did time itself start at the Big Bang? If so, what does “before” even mean? Science provides models, but not ultimate answers. And it is within this boundary of knowledge that deeper philosophical questions emerge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Physics Becomes a Way of Thinking</title>
      <link>https://aminphysicsai.github.io/posts/chapter-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminphysicsai.github.io/posts/chapter-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chapter One: When Physics Becomes a Way of Thinking&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Consciousness, Mathematics, Emotion, and the Silent Intelligence of Nature&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article marks the beginning of a chapter-wise series, written not merely to study physics, but to experience it as a philosophy of existence. Here, physics is not reduced to formulas and problem-solving techniques. Instead, it is approached as a deep lens through which reality, consciousness, emotions, and nature reveal their hidden unity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Physics Becomes a Way of Thinking</title>
      <link>https://aminphysicsai.github.io/posts/chapter04/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://aminphysicsai.github.io/posts/chapter04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Physics Becomes a Way of Thinking&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Physics sirf ek subject nahi hai. Physics ek nazariya hai. Ek tareeqa hai dekhne ka, sochne ka, aur existence ko samajhne ka. Jab physics equations se aage badh kar perception ban jaati hai, tab woh sirf mechanics, thermodynamics ya electromagnetism nahi rehti — woh thinking ka structure ban jaati hai.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sab kuch fields se shuru hota hai. Space khaali nahi hota. Har jagah ek dynamic structure present hota hai — fields. In fields me disturbance hoti hai, aur disturbance vibration ke roop me propagate karti hai. Stable vibration ko hum particle kehte hain. Yani matter ek solid cheez nahi, balki sustained oscillation hai.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
